# Ellis Enobun

# **Front End Developer**

E-mail: elnobun@gmail.com

Github: http://github.com/elnobun LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/ellisenobun

Portfolio: https://ellisenobun.com Mobile: 07954850837

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Front End: HTML5, CSS3/SCSS, Javascript (ES6), React/Redux, Nuxtjs, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap,

Wordpress.

Back End: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, RESTful API.

Design Tools: Adobe XD, Figma

Version Control: GIT, Github, Netlify, Vercel,

**Techniques:** Agile Development, Responsive Design, MVC Architecture

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:**

Personal Portfolio: Tech Stack: React, SCSS, Typescript.

<u>Movie Search Website</u>: This project uses React and "themoviedb" API services. Users can search for their favourite movies and see previews. I am currently adding more features like selecting films based on genre and release dates, the ability to watch a clip and save it for later and the ability to filter movies by rating.

<u>PureDrinks Co. E-commerce Website</u>: Worked with a team of UX/UI Designers and Project Managers to design this website for a UK Company called PureDrinks UK. PureDrinks Co. specialises in organic drinks with health benefits. Over the last few months, since the website launched, the company has seen a massive change in their ROI (Return On Investments). The customer conversion rate also increased. This project showcases how powerful WordPress is in setting up an E-Commerce website and making it functional for commercial use.

<u>London Rangers Community Charity</u>: A Charity website for the London Rangers Community Football Club UK.

<u>Budget Manager Application</u>: This project showcases the power of combining technologies like Reactjs, Momentjs and SCSS preprocessor. I created this application to keep track of my spending.

<u>Contact Manager Application</u>: *Tech Stack*: Javascript, JSON REST API

Please see ellisenobun.com/projects for more.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Web Developer / Product Analyst

Digital Echos, UK.

Since Sept 2019

- Key responsibilities were to develop and maintain new websites for clients. Projects included building <u>Puredrinks Company E-Commerce Website</u> and project managing the building of <u>London Rangers Community Charity</u> website, with more than 80% on-time delivery while staying 7% under budget.
- Actively involved in the entire development lifecycle of projects; documenting system requirements, user requirements, use cases, user stories, wireframing design, coding and deployment.
- Handled technical issues on websites, ensuring websites are AAA compliant and Accessible, with standard SEO practices.
- Collaborated with a team of developers to redesign the <u>Company Website</u>, resulting in a reduction of 20% load times and a 15% increase in user accessibility.
- Frontiered, the transition from a waterfall method of web development to a more efficient agile methodology, achieving an 80% increase in client satisfaction, data prediction and web development cycle.
- Executed tests daily, created defect report and fixed bugs in web applications while ensuring proper documentation and information in all stages of a product life cycle.

#### **Freelance Web Developer**

DevHype, UK.

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019

- Initiated user-friendly E-Commerce websites, including an optimised check-out page, resulting in increased user clicks and a 33% increase in customer purchases.
- Enforced HTTPS and SSL Management, to ensure clients website is working over an encrypted connection, thereby increasing website security by 100%.
- Created interactive websites that guaranteed high traffic, page views, and total user experience, generating a 45% increase in client sales revenue.
- Diagnosed and troubleshoot various critical clients' websites by weekly updating legacy code of existing sites, to improve performance and accessibility.
- Integrated a daily and weekly backup schedule to protect websites.

#### **Code Mentor / Reviewer**

Udacity Inc. Mountain View & Sans Francisco, CA.

Jun 2016 - Nov 2017

- Reviewed code (new and existing) weekly to ensure quality assurance, web standards conformity, and responsibility for the code quality.
- Collaborated with a team of 6 to implement a Project Toolkit to help students fit into the digital programme by ascertaining strengths and weaknesses to boost student coding experience.
- Offered online support to students daily through a dedicated dashboard to improve industry standards' coding styles and skills.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Masters Degree**

The University of Leicester - Leicester City, United Kingdom Oct 2011 - Nov 2013

### **COURSES & TRAINING**

# **FullStack Web Development:**

Udacity Inc. Mountain View, United States. Jan 2016 - May 2016

**LANGUAGES:** English Language